这就像是你能遭受的
it's like the most severe spinal
最严重的脊髓损伤
cord injury you can have
当他们告诉我瘫痪了时
when they told me I was paralyzed
我告诉他们我没有瘫痪
I told them that I wasn't paralyzed
当时我儿子在加拿大
so  my son was in Canada
当时他正在打一场冰球
and he was playing a hockey
参加一个冰球锦标赛
game in a hockey tournament
他的冰刀卡在了冰缝里
he caught an edge
接着他整个人飞了出去
and he threw
脸朝前重重地撞在了围板上
he flew like face first into the boards
现场恰好有一名消防员
there happened to be a firefighter
他在现场为他进行了插管
that was there that was able to incubate him
因为他当时停止呼吸长达八分钟左右
because he did not breathe for like eight minutes
周六早上
Saturday morning
大概是凌晨三点钟左右
probably at like 3:00am
他的事故发生在晚上 10 点
his accident was at 10 o'clock at night
嗯
um
一位神经外科医生进行了手术，融合了他的 C1 和 C2 椎骨
a neurosurgeon went in and they fused his C1 and C2
也就是脊柱的最顶端
which is at the top of your spinal cord
就在脑干的旁边
so it would be like right next to your brainstem
他当时没有知觉，而且
he had no feeling and he was
被认为属于完全性严重损伤
considered a complete severe injury
所以他们说康复无望
so they said there was no hope of recovery
于是我问了医生
so like I had asked the doctors
比如几率是不是只有十分之一
you know the chances like one in 10
他们说绝对不行
they said absolutely not
而在那个时候
and at this point
他必须依赖呼吸机
he is vent dependent
依赖鼻饲管
feeding tube dependent
我们被告知他永远无法再进食或饮水
we're told he's never gonna eat or drink
或者能够独立呼吸
or be able to breathe independently
我有一个朋友，她跟我说，嘿
I had a friend and she's like hey
我知道有这么个东西，据说
I know of this thing that's supposed
对脊髓损伤有帮助
to help spinal cord injuries
而且它有助于减轻吞咽困难
and it helps reduce the swallowing
然后我想，好吧
and I'm like OK
也许我们可以试试那个
well  maybe we can try that
因为在那个时候
because at this point
我们已经没有任何选择了
we didn't have any options
当你受了这么严重的伤时
when you have an injury this severe
基本上就是，大家一直在给我发
you're basically like people are sending me
Neuralink 相关的东西，想让他植入脑机接口芯片
Neuralink things to like put a brain chip in
但我们决定先尝试局部外用
we decided to try it topically
我们买了一个那种小滚珠瓶装的
we bought like a little rollerball one
我就直接涂抹在他的皮肤上，因为
and I would just rub it on his skin because
它看起来有点像个乳液球
it kind of looks like a lotion ball
当时谁也没觉得有什么异常
nobody thought anything of it
我当时就在他身上涂抹这种二甲基亚砜（DMSO）
I was just rubbing this DMSO on his body
我们是在第 4 天或第 5 天开始用的
we started that on day 4 or 5
到了第 7 天的时候
and by day seven
我会戳戳他的脚或腿
I would poke his feet or his legs
然后他会睁开眼睛
and he would open his eyes
因为他们给他用了异丙酚之类的药
cause they have him on like propofol  um
还有芬太尼，不管他们给你用的是什么药
fat now whatever kinds of drugs they put you on
反正药量很大
it's a lot of drugs  so
他现在神志还不太清醒，我是说
he's pretty out of it  I mean
他在重症监护室里待了 21 天，我想
he was in ICU for 21 days there  and I think
他还以为只过了三天，所以
he thought it was three days  so
但我会开始戳戳他
but I would start poking him
然后他就会醒过来
and he would wake up
或者他会对我戳他的腿部和手臂做出反应
or he would respond to me poking his legs and arms
他的伤势可能曾处于完全性损伤状态
he was probably a complete injury for
大约持续了 21 到 24 天
probably 21 to 24 days
直到我们转入中级监护病房（Step-down ICU）
it wasn't until we made it to the step down
他的伤势才转为不完全性损伤，然后
ICU that he became an incomplete injury  and then
当时有一名物理治疗师在陪他训练
there was a PT working with him and
她感觉到他的髋屈肌有了反应
she felt his hip flexor fire
他们当时都惊呆了，心想“我的天呐”
and they're like oh my gosh
他从 Asia A 级恢复到了 Asia C 级
he went from an Asia a to an Asia C
这通常被认为是不可能发生的
which usually is not supposed to happen
你要么是严重的脊髓
you're either a severe spinal
损伤，完全没有感觉，什么都没有
cord injury with no sensation  nothing
就像 ASIA A 级一样
like an Asia A
你不可能直接从 A 级恢复到 C 级
you don't go from an a to a C  from there
而他当时处于 A 级和 C 级之间
he was A's and C's
我现在一有机会
and I'm still rubbing this stuff
还是会往他身上抹这东西，我是说
on him every chance I get  I mean
我大概一天会往那儿抹上 10 次
I would rub that thing on him probably 10 times a day
有趣的是，我抹在他身体左侧的
what's interesting is I was able to rub it on his
次数要比右侧多得多
left side of his body more than his right side
他的左侧显然更有力一些
his left side is definitely stronger
右侧则是他之前连接呼吸机的方式
on the right is the way his ventilator
大概持续了前六个月的时间
was for probably the first 6 months
所以当他连着呼吸机时
so when he was hooked up to the ventilator
我实际上无法在右侧涂抹 DMSO
I couldn't actually get the DMSO on the right side
我们还在继续使用它
we're still using it
右侧正在慢慢恢复
the right side is slowly coming back
四个月前，他这一侧的手部握力
his hand grip on this side was like one pound
大约只有一磅
probably four months ago
而现在已经增加到了 20 磅
and now it's up to 20 pounds
他确实已经掌握了每一项精细运动技能
he literally has every single like fine motor skill
我们现在的任务是加强这些技能
it's a matter of us now strengthening that
距离他受伤已经过去 16 个月了
he is 16 months out from his injury
他已经三周没用过轮椅了
and he hasn't used his wheelchair in three weeks
现在是十月份
now in October
我记得是在十月底
I think the end of October
他迈出了第一步
he took his first steps
当时是借助一个大的
and it was with like a big
Argo 助行器
Argo walker
然后到了十一月左右
and then like in November
我们改用平台式助行器
we move to a platform walker
一月或二月
January or February
二月时我们改用普通的助行器
February we move to like a normal walker
然后就在
and then just in
五月我们改用腋下拐杖，现在正在进行康复治疗
may we move to the arm crutches and now in therapy
他正在练习在不使用腋下拐杖的情况下行走
he's working on walking without the arm crutches
我们当时还依赖呼吸机
we were like ventilator dependent
依赖药物治疗
medication dependent
我儿子已经停掉了大部分
my son's off of most of his
药物，而在这之前他可能要吃像..
medications before he was probably on like
以前要吃 50 或 60 种药，而现在
50 or 60 medications and now we're
我们已经减到只剩背部用药了
down to just the back of it
我儿子是我见过的极少数
my son is one of the only people I've met that
在这种病情下却没有神经性疼痛的人
does not have the nerve pain with his condition
所以他已经停掉了所有的神经止痛药
so he is off of all nerve pain meds
如果你让一群
there's no money to be made off of it if you
能够自理的“行走的高位截瘫患者”
have a bunch of walking quadriplegics that
到处跑，那是赚不到钱的
are self sufficient running around